Finding Aid for St. George’s Episcopal Church (Warren, Mich.) records, 1955-2008
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
St. George’s Episcopal Church (Warren, Mich.) records 1955-2008
St. George’s Episcopal Church (Warren, Mich.)
1.75 linear feet and 1 oversize volume.
2008075 Ba 2
St. George Episcopal Church of Warren, Michigan, member of the Episcopal Diocese of Michigan, operated from 1927 to 2007. Papers include a complete record of baptisms, burials, confirmations, marriages, and vestry minutes.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated by the Episcopal Diocese of Michigan (donor no. 1059 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
St. George's was established as a Parochial Mission of Christ Church in Grosse Pointe, Michigan during the era of rapid population growth in the Warren -- Center Line area in 1955. The mission was received into the Diocese of Michigan in February of that year. Groundbreaking ceremonies were held for a church building on the corner of East Ten Mile Road and Lorraine in December of 1956. The church adopted a Vietnamese family in 1976. St. George's Mission became a parish in 1966 and held its last service on January 6 2008.
The record group is comprised of two series: Historical and Genealogical records, and Organizational files.
Subjects:
Episcopal Church--Michigan--Warren.; St. George's Episcopal Church (Warren, Mich.); Warren (Mich.)--Church history.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Historical and Genealogical
  The Historical and Genealogical series (0.5 linear feet and 1 oversize volume) contains a complete record of baptisms, burial, confirmations, and marriages, dating from 1955.
  - A Celebration of the Life of St. George Episcopal Church, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Gift Register, 1955-2000 (Box 1)
  - Guest Register, 1974-1993 (Box 1)
  - Registers
    (incl. Communicants, Baptisms, Confirmations, Marriages, and Burials)
    - 1955-1958 (Box 1)
      (vol. no. 1)
    - 1958-1963 (Box 1)
      (vol. no. 2)
    - 1963-1999 (Volume 3)
      (vol. no. 3)
    - 2000-2004 (Box 1)
      (vol. no. 4)
- Organizational
  The Organizational series (1.25 linear feet) contains a complete collection of registers of church services, which record attendance, as well as minutes from the vestry committee. Also extant are church blueprints, diagrams, and other items related to the construction of church buildings, as well as a small number of photographs.
  - Annual Meetings, 1955-1963 (Box 1)
  - Audited Statements of Cash Receipts and Disbursements, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Church Inventory Photographs, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Construction
    - Blueprints and Diagrams (Box 1)
    - Building and Planning Committee Minutes, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
    - Site Development Proposal, 1964-1966 (incl. blueprints) (Box 1)
  - Corporation Paperwork, 1966-1996 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1955-1964, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Parking Lot Expansion, 2005-2006 (incl. photographs) (Box 1)
  - Property Sale, Deeds, Land Contract, Surveys, etc.
    - 1988-1990, 1994 (Box 1)
    - 1995-2001 (incl. photographs) (Box 1)
  - Rector's Committee Minutes, 1955-1960 (Box 1)
  - Register of Church Services (incl. attendance counts)
    - 1955-1964 (Box 2)
    - 1964-2008, 4 volumes (Box 2)
  - Vestry Minutes
    - 1961-1970, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - 1980-2007, 4 folders (Box 2)